

# Martin Holmgren

## **Details**

Rankhyttan 50

791 92 Falun

Sweden

+46 70 5429002

martin@teamholmgren.com

**NATIONALITY** 

Swedish

**BORN / PLACE** 

23-04-1975 / Vänersborg

### **COMPETENCIES**

- Logistics and infrastructure
- Supply Chain
- Research and development
- Purchase and supplier relations
- Sales and customer relations
- Innovation
- Sustainable forestry
- Strategy development
- Strategy execution
- Coaching
- International collaborations
- Management team work
- Board work
- Line and Matrix organizations
- Organizational development
- LEAN development
- Leadership and people development
- Culture development
- Crisis management
- Media management
- Union negotiations
- Collaboration Indigenous people
- Public Affairs and policy processes

### **Profile**

Dedicated and experienced leader with broad knowledge. Solid experience from leading and developing business and people from both a board and an executive perspective. Engaged communicator known for inclusive leadership and with the ability to collaborate with operational and administrative staff as well as the research community.

Analytical and strategic ability combined with an interest in details when necessary. A visionary team player who both represents the team while at the same time being part of it.

# Work experience

### **Operational roles:**

CEO and owner TEAM Holmgren AB. Consultant, senior advisor, coach, 2022-

CEO Stora Enso Skog AB, Senior Vice President, Head of Forest Sweden Stora Enso, 2010-2022

Regional Manager Stora Enso Skog AB, 2008-2010

Transport Manager Stora Enso Skog AB, 2004-2008

Operational Transport Manager Stora Enso Skog AB, 2002-2004

Transport Supervisor Stora Enso Skog AB, 1999-2002

Researcher Skogforsk, 1999-1999

### **Board roles and committees:**

Chairman board of Sydved AB, 2010-2022

Chairman board of Stora Enso Bioenergi AB, 2010-2022

Chairman board of Skogforsk, 2020-2022

Board member Skogforsk, 2016-2020

Board member Biometria ek.förening, 2018-2021

Board member Research program Future Forests, 2013-2017

Member Forest committee, Swedish Forest Industries Federation, 2010-2022

Chairman Swedish forestry steering group for game damage 2019-2022

### Education

TIO Program – SSE Stockholm School of economics, 2022

Pathbreaker Program – IMD Lausanne Switzerland, 2015

Lead Through People – Stora Enso Manager Program, 2014

Forum Novare – Novare Leadership Academy, 2013

FEM Program – IFL Stockholm School of economics, 2005

Jägmästare/M. Sc in Forestry – SLU, Swedish University of Agricultural sciences, 1999

Teknisk linje, Nils Ericson gymnasiet, Trollhättan, 1994

### References

Provided on request